<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>networking on Peyton Walters</title>
    <link>https://pawalt.github.io/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in networking on Peyton Walters</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Peyton Walters</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pawalt.github.io/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Caplance Development Update 3</title>
      <link>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2019/07/caplance-development-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2019/07/caplance-development-update-3/</guid>
      <description>🎉 We made it! 🎉 After 6 months of work, Caplance is finally at MVP. The brief release notes can be found here.
To get to MVP, I had to implement the following functionality:
 Logging Config file parsing  Combining all the previous updates, we get the following feature set for the MVP:
 Packet listening Packet forwarding over UDP Direct reply from backends, allowing the load balancer to only have to handle incoming traffic Dynamic backend registration and deregistration Backend commands and health checks Logging Config file parsing  I&amp;rsquo;ll briefly cover the improvements so far and then give a short demo of Caplance working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caplance Development Update 2</title>
      <link>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2019/06/caplance-development-update-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2019/06/caplance-development-update-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back! Over the past few weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve had much more time to work on Caplance than I had in the prior months, so, naturally, a ton of work has gotten done in these few weeks. Specifically, I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented the following functionality:
 Backend registration The following controls from the backends:  PAUSE DEREGISTER RESUME HEALTH  caplancectl to tell a running client process to issue one of those commands Graceful stop for backends Packet listening on NFQUEUE Refactor project structure  If you&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping track, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that this puts us very close to the Caplance MVP!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFQUEUE and the Mysterious RESET</title>
      <link>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2019/06/nfqueue-and-the-mysterious-reset/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2019/06/nfqueue-and-the-mysterious-reset/</guid>
      <description>While working on my load balancer, Caplance, I ran into a very strange error when trying to establish a connection between a client and a backend. Before I go to deep, though, let me give a quick intro into how TCP connection establishment works.
Types of Message When establishing a TCP connection, there are 4 possible packet types you could see:
 SYN (S in tcpdump) - Always the first message sent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caplance Development Update 1</title>
      <link>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2019/05/caplance-development-update-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2019/05/caplance-development-update-1/</guid>
      <description>After countless hours spent reading the GoDocs, googling &amp;ldquo;gre packets golang&amp;rdquo;, and staring at the term SIGSEV, I&amp;rsquo;ve got an update! I&amp;rsquo;ve made pretty significant progress on the actual load balancer, implementing most of the base functionality. So far, the load balancer can:
 listen for and ingest whole IP packets select the backend for a packet based on a combination of IP and source port encapsulate packets in UDP and send them to the appropriate backend attach a specified virtual IP  I&amp;rsquo;ve also implemented some extremely rudimentary testing and setup, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to rework those once the project structure solidifies some more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mininet for Education</title>
      <link>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2019/04/mininet-for-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2019/04/mininet-for-education/</guid>
      <description>For about 2 years, I built and led the NEAT Rack Project, a program meant to teach high school and college aged students network engineering. In this program, we covered things as basic as introduction to Linux and as advanced as firewalling or dynamic routing with BGP. This program was well-run, well-written, and it overall did a solid job of giving students an introduction to technology infrastructure. There was just one problem with it - hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maglev - A Next-Generation Load Balancer</title>
      <link>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2019/04/maglev-a-next-generation-load-balancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2019/04/maglev-a-next-generation-load-balancer/</guid>
      <description>When reading Google&amp;rsquo;s SRE book, I came across the section on load balancing. The book breaks up load balancing into three levels:
 DNS level Network level/Virtual IP level Datacenter level  While I was familiar with the Datacenter level (aka reverse proxy load balancing) and DNS load balancing (achieved partially through round robin DNS), I had never looked at network-level load balancing. After reading this section, I was fascinated with how their network-level load balancing works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPLS with OpenBSD</title>
      <link>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2018/01/vpls-with-openbsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawalt.github.io/posts/2018/01/vpls-with-openbsd/</guid>
      <description>VPLS is extremely useful in allowing multiple sites to be connected to a single bridged domain. Unfortunately, VPLS networks are typically implemented with proprietary technology like a Cisco router. OpenBSD lets us break free of the typical restrictions of proprietary technology and use 100% free software to make a full-fledged VPLS network.
Why VPLS? With VPLS, you can deliver a layer 2 circuit over a routed backbone. This lets you extend that circuit from one location to another over a route that you can easily control.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>